Count Sebring.
ゼブリン伯爵　ラフィア伯爵　オルガ伯爵
Count Raffia.
Count Orga.
Thank you for allowing me
to intrude upon your valuable time.
この度はご多忙の中　お集まりいただき　ありがとうございます
I am sorry for your loss, Count Troyard.
痛み入ります　トロイヤード伯爵
ザーツバルム卿は残念だった
Count Saazbaum's passing was a great tragedy.
Yes.
My father owed much to him.
お父上には生前大変世話になった
If there is anything I can do to help,
my assistance is yours.
できることがあれば　協力は惜しまん
Thank you for your kind words.
お気遣い　感謝いたします
However, this is not the time
to give in to personal feelings.
しかし今は　個人の感傷に浸っている場合ではありません
Most admirable.
これは殊勝な
今こそ我ら軌道騎士　一丸となって地球侵攻を推し進める時
Now is the time for the Orbital Knights
to unite and launch a renewed offensive.
That is the best way to honor Count Saazbaum.
それこそは　ザーツバルム卿への最大の手向け
I agree.
はい　すべての船が同じ方向を目指して進まねばなりません
We must all set our ships upon the same course.
Ah, now I see.
なるほど
Do you mean to take the helm, then?
で　君がその舵取りをする　と？
If you would honor me thus.
僭越ながら
That aside,
時に　マリルシャン伯爵と決闘をなさるそうだな
I am given to understand that
you will duel Count Marylcian?
Such infighting strikes me as the precise opposite of unity.
一丸となる時に　争いはどうかと思うが
What say you, Count Troyard?
どうかな　トロイヤード伯爵
"No lowly Terran..."
地球人風情が…
"No lowly Terran could ever be a match for the mighty Vers."
地球人風情が我らヴァースに敵うはずもない
That conviction makes you inattentive.
その思い込みが隙を生み
It makes you careless.
綻びを作り　やがて大きな穴となって
It makes you negligent.
And ultimately, it becomes your undoing.
いつしか決壊する
それが今の軌道騎士です
Such are the Orbital Knights right now.
口が過ぎるのではないか　トロイヤード卿
Watch your mouth, Count Troyard!
As you are aware, I was not born on Vers.
ご承知のように　私はヴァースの生まれではありません
However, it is easier to see some things from an outside perspective.
しかし　輪の外にいるからこそ　見えるものもあります
此度の決闘も軌道騎士の思い上がりによるもの
And I believe it is my duty to punish the hubris that lead to this particular duel.
それを戒めるのが私の責任かと
なるほど　一理ある
Very well.
You have a point.
Count Orga!
オルガ卿
確かに認めがたい
It is difficult to admit,
but he is right.
だが　事実だ
Partly, at least.
少なくともその一部だ
I shall leave the matter to your discretion, Count Troyard.
貴公に委ねよう　トロイヤード卿
トライデント基地襲撃は見事だった
Your attack on Trident Base was magnificent.
Count Sebring.
ゼブリン伯爵　ラフィア伯爵
Count Raffia.
Thank you for bearing with my incivility.
数々の無礼な発言　ご傾聴いただき　感謝いたします
kimi no te ga hirogeta nani mo nai sora yo
Your hands spread out the vast and empty sky
君の手が広げた　何もない空よ
rikutsu no umi dake no kai wo asobeba
when you played with what the sea of reason would give
理屈の海だけの　解を遊べば
hodoite wa koboreta tagai no namida
Our tears welled up and fell
ほどいては溢れた　お互いのナミダ
kouka shita kotoba uso kimagure
Words, lies, and whim down from orbit
降下した言葉・嘘・キマグレ
soul art
Soul art
soul・art　リズムを奏でて
rhythm kanadete
We play a song now
aizu wo ringu ni tsunagu
and connect the signs to a ring
合図をリングに繋ぐ
形だけのシステムと
katachi dake no system to
A system of pure shape
katami dake no majinai mo
A magic spell without power
形見だけの呪いも
toubounin no hajirai on
The sound of shy fugitives
逃亡人の恥じらい音
想像Drive　CarryOn　意地なTIRE
souzou drive carryon iji na tire
Carry on imagining, don't give up
gokai aru doa ni zero ga nemurikaketa
We're running out of false doors
誤解あるドアに　ゼロが眠りかけた
tokei daita hito to tenshi
Men and angels embrace the passage of time
時計抱いた人と天使
towa ni aku doorutachi
They are dolls who gave up on eternity,
永久に飽くドール達
mata onaji kaze ni mogaite
fighting against this recurring fever
また同じ風邪に　モガいて
巡航ミサイル　全弾迎撃された模様です
All cruise missiles appear to have been intercepted.
I don't think a saturation attack is going to work.
飽和攻撃は無理のようですね
セルナキス伯爵のカタフラクト　灼熱のソリス
Count Selnakis' Cataphract is Scorching Solis.
It mounts a directed energy weapon with enough range to reach the satellite belt,
搭載された光学兵器の射程は　サテライトベルトまで届き
航空支援も不可能
so we cannot provide air support.
とんだ化け物だ
It's monstrous.
強襲部隊より入電　まもなく上陸します
Message from the assault squad.
They're making landfall.
Launch cruise missiles.
巡航ミサイル発射　注意を引き付けろ
Keep him distracted.
Guess we have no choice but to brawl it out.
結局懐に飛び込む以外ねえってか
全機搭乗
Mount your frames!
みんな　出撃準備よ
Get ready to sortie!
Inko?
韻子？
韻子
Inko!
Yes?
はい？
どうしたの
What's wrong?
Nothing.
ううん
Hey, Rayet...
ね　ライエ
What?
何
Remember the manhunt the other day?
この間急に捜索かかったじゃない？
For... uh...
えっと　マ…ママ…
Count Mazuurek?
マズゥールカ伯爵
Right!
そう
Do you have any idea how he escaped?
どうやって逃げたんだろう
Nah.
さあ
I wouldn't be surprised if Inaho figured it out.
伊奈帆なら分かるかな
Why?
どうして？
尋問に行ったし
Well, he went to interrogate him.
Did he mention anything?
何か聞いてない？
何も
Nope.
Okay...
そう
出撃　行くわよ
Time for battle.
Yeah.
韻子　ごめん
I'm sorry, Inko.
たったこれだけの仕掛けで方位が示せるとは
How fascinating that such a simple mechanism
can indicate one's bearing.
Oh, the wonders of a planet with a magnetic field.
磁気を持つ惑星ならではの装置だな
さて　トロイヤード伯爵と界塚伊奈帆
Let's see...
Count Troyard and Kaizuka Inaho.
どちらも地球の少年　信用に足るものか
Can either child of Earth be trusted?
シンプル故に迷わぬということか
When something is simple enough, it cannot be led astray.
真理だな
Isn't that right?
本当に決闘などを行うのですか　スレイン
Will you really duel him, Slaine?
Yes.
はい　挑まれた以上逃げるわけにはいきません
I cannot back down from this challenge.
私が　マリルシャン伯爵の来訪を許したせいですね
This all happened because I allowed Count Marylcian to dock.
No.
いいえ
Rather, I should thank you.
レムリナ姫のおかげです
You've given me a chance to prove my valor.
私の力を示す良い機会です
この決闘に勝利すれば
Should I prove victorious, it will discourage opposition from the other Orbital Knights.
私に反発する軌道騎士たちへの牽制になるでしょう
決してご心配には及びません
You need not worry.
いずれは　本当にあなたの夢が叶うかもしれませんね
Your dream might yet come true, it seems.
I have no dreams.
私に夢など…
蔑まれていた地球人が　ヴァースの実権を握る
The Terran once held in contempt will one day rule Vers.
初めてお会いした時から　ずっと思っていました
Ever since we first met,
あなたと私は　どこか似ていると
I've felt that you and I were kindred spirits.
王族への遺恨　ずっとお忘れにならないおつもりですか
Do you still hold on to your grudge against the royal family?
Yes.
ええ　ヴァース血族に縁のないあなたが力をつけてゆくのは
I find it highly gratifying to see someone with no connection to the royal family at all, like you,
gaining political power.
とても小気味良いことだわ
あなたも　ずっと忘れないでいるのでしょう
And I think there's something you'll never let go, too.
お姉様のこと
Namely, my sister.
本当にお慕いしてるのですね
You seem to genuinely love her.
もし…
Would you allow me to help you?
私でよろしければ　お手伝いさせていただけませんか
構いません…
I don't mind being her substitute.
お姉様の代わりでも
各小隊　報告
All platoons, report!
ベルジアン小隊　配置よし
Belgian Platoon, in position.
Maremmano Platoon, in position.
マレンマーノ小隊　配置よし
Pottok Platoon, in position.
ボトク小隊　配置よし
Lokai Platoon, in position.
ロカイ小隊　配置よし
Mustang Platoon, in position.
マスタング小隊　配置よし
You can't dodge his energy beam.
奴の光学兵器は避けようがない
If he spots you, consider yourself dead.
見つかったら終わりだと思え
作戦開始
Begin operation!
That smokescreen scatters all wavelengths from infrared to radar, huh?
赤外線からレーダー波まで撹乱する煙幕か
Cheap tricks.
猿知恵だな
What the hell?
何だと
Fools!
愚か者め
Clydesdale Leader to all units!
クライスデールリーダーより小隊各機へ
南側に散開　煙幕を張れ
Move to the southern shore and keep the smoke up!
What a waste of time.
無駄なことを
Fire, fire, fire!
撃て　撃て　撃て
Keep his attention on us!
こちらに注意を引き付けろ
Don't get hit!
当たるなよ
引き付けと言って当たらないようにってどうすればいいのよ
How are we supposed to do that?!
なお君は？
Where's Nao?
上げるわよ　気をつけて
I'll lift you up.
Be careful.
ライエさん
Rayet?
オーケー　中継する
Okay.
Patching you through.
音響解析　敵座標確定
Running sonar.
Enemy located.
目標　29951103
Target is at 29.951103, -90.085579.
-90085579
Roger that.
了解　照準合わせ
Targeting location.
Firing.
発射
Got it.
発射　了解
Counting down.
カウントダウン…
Five.
Four.
Three.
Two.
One.
What?!
何だ
Impact.
着弾
Adjust 037, 025.
修正　037　025
It came from the sea?
海から…
Fire.
撃て
Naval guns?!
艦砲射撃か
It missed us.
外れ…
光学兵器は　直線でしか攻撃できません
Beam weapons only fire in a straight line.
He can't hit us if we hide beyond the horizon.
地球の丸みに隠れれば　届かない
But we can still hit him because our shells travel in a parabola due to gravity.
しかし　こちらの砲弾は地球の引力で放物線を描くので
水平線の陰にも届くと
照準さえ可能ならば
As long as we have a spotter, that is.
Adjust 283, -472.
修正　283　-472
Fire ultra-high-speed rounds!
超高速弾　撃て
おのれ　観測衛星もなしに　どうやって正確に座標を
How can they be so accurate
without observation satellites?
Is that it?
これか
The UAVs that were relaying our
laser comms have been taken out!
レーザー通信を中継していた無人機がやられました
We've lost contact with Second Lieutenant Kaizuka!
界塚少尉と連絡が取れません
Rayet!
ライエさん
曳光弾だ　僕の言う通りに撃って
Switch to tracer rounds.
Fire them exactly as I tell you.
Over there, huh?
そこか
Nao!
なお君
You bastard!
この…
Tracer rounds!
曳光弾です
その距離から　このソリスを仕留められるとでも？
Do you seriously think you can bring down my Solis from that distance?
ユキ姉　逃げて
Yuki, get clear!
Warrant Officer Kaizuka!
界塚准尉
Stay back!
来ちゃだめ
Crap!
くっそ
2発　続いて3発
Second and third volley ready!
修正　002　003
Adjust 002, 003. Fire!
撃て
Kaizuka!
界塚
そうよ　そうやってそこで偉そうにしてなさい
Just like that!
Stand right there and give me a speech!
灼熱の輝きにて　灰になるがいい
May you be purified by my scorching fire!
Go ahead and fire, frog-face!
撃ってきなさいよ　このカエル頭
ユキ姉
Yuki!
大丈夫　片腕やられただけ
I'm fine.
I just lost an arm.
What about you guys?
そっちは
We're all right.
平気　界塚少尉も無事です
Second Lieutenant Kaizuka is unhurt too.
よかった
That's great news.
よくないよ
No, it isn't.
逃げてって言ったのに
I told you to get clear.
Why did you ignore my order, Warrant Officer?
命令違反だよ　界塚准尉
Don't order me around just because you're a higher rank.
何よ　階級が上だからって偉そうにしない
いや　偉いから
That's the... point of ranks...
姉に命令できる弟なんていません
No little brother can ever order his big sister around.
Clydesdale Leader to all units.
クライスデールリーダーより各機
Mission complete.
作戦終了　これより帰投する
Return to base.
These are flowers called "roses" that bloom on Earth.
地球に咲く　バラという花です
Is something the matter?
どうかしましたか
決闘など大丈夫なのですか　スレイン様
Is this duel really such a good idea, Sir Slaine?
I've fought for my life many times before.
命のやり取りは　今まで何度も経験しています
But...
でも…
Are you worried about me, Eddelrittuo?
心配してくれるのですか　エデルリッゾさん
前はよく僕のことを睨んでたのに
You were always so suspicious of me, too.
That was a long time ago.
昔のことです
バラには　いろいろな花言葉があるんです
Roses symbolize many different things.
Red roses represent love,
赤いバラは「あなたを愛しています」
while blue roses represent miracles.
青いバラの意味は「奇跡」
Miracles...
奇跡…
でも　青いバラにはもう一つの意味があるんです
Blue roses have another meaning, though.
That one...
それが…
それが真実かもしれません
That one might apply here.
Let us be off.
参りましょうか
ハーシェル　出撃
Herschel, launching!
Best of luck, Sir Slaine.
御武運を　スレイン様
タルシス　出る
Tharsis, launching!
卑しきものの高慢なる振る舞い　目にあまります
It disgusts me to see a plebeian act as though he is in charge.
On the honor of the Vers Orbital Knights, I shall mete out your punishment.
ヴァース軌道騎士の名誉にかけて　成敗いたしましょう
Your self-serving attempt to seize an official post
disturbs order as well as peace.
私利私欲のため　みだりに官職を奪う行為
秩序ばかりか　治安も乱します
姫の警護を司る者として　制裁します
As he who is charged with Her Highness' well-being, I will right this injustice.
これより　マリルシャン伯爵とトロイヤード伯爵の決闘を行う
The duel between Count Marylcian and Count Troyard will now begin.
始め
Go!
You like to run, just as they say!
噂通り　逃げ足の早いこと
しかし　このハーシェルの攻撃から逃げ切れますかな
But how long can you flee
from my Herschel's attacks?
スレイン様
Sir Slaine!
Regardless of your predictive abilities, even you cannot avoid this many!
いくら予測ができようと
この数では対処できないでしょう
What?
なに…
I see. Perhaps your mind is not as feeble as I thought.
なるほど　多少は知恵の回る
しかし…
Nonetheless...
儚い　儚い　儚いなぁ
Vain! Vain!
Vainly you struggle!
青いバラの花言葉は　「奇跡」
Blue roses symbolize miracles.
もう一つの意味は
But they can also mean...
「不可能」
impossibility.
本当に　もうダメなのですか
Is it really impossible?
本当に　もうお目覚めにならないのですか
Will you never wake from your slumber after all?
どうか…
Please...
どうか　奇跡を…
Grant us a miracle!
That's right.
そう
不可能なんだ
It's impossible.
I believe in you!
信じています
奇跡など起きはしない
There are no miracles!
Slaine!
スレイン
逃げるしか能がないのか
Is running all you can do?
この劣等民族め
Inferior scum!
伊奈帆　なにを見てるの？
Inaho?
What are you looking at?
戦闘している
A fight.
えっ　どこ？
Huh?
Where?
There's nowhere left to run!
逃げ場はありませんよ
Indeed. For you.
逃げ道がないのはあなたです
ハーシェル最大の武器は　全周囲からの同時攻撃
The Herschel's greatest weapon is
an attack from all directions at once.
しかしここでは　攻撃は一方向からに限定される
But in here, your attack angle is limited to one.
月面基地建築時に使用した資材搬入路
Many material loading tunnels remain from the moon base's construction.
ここを探していた
I've been exploring them.
貴様ごときに…
You're nothing but a plebeian!
この私が…
I am a knight!
Know your place, Terran!
なめるな　地球人
勝者…
The victor...
トロイヤード伯爵
is Count Troyard.
掟に則り
As per the rules of the duel,
マリルシャン伯爵の資産はすべて
Count Marylcian's estate shall be transferred to Count Slaine Saazbaum Troyard.
スレイン・ザーツバルム・トロイヤード伯爵に譲渡される事となります
よろしいですか
I trust you have no objections?
このバルークルス　立会人として確かに見届けた
As official witness, I, Barouhcruz, acknowledge the outcome.
終わった
And it's done.
何でも見えるんだね　伊奈帆は
You can see everything, Inaho.
うん
Yeah.
でも　本当に知りたいことは　なにも見えないんだ
Everything except what I most want to.
韻子　ごめん
I'm sorry, Inko.
Huh?
巻き込みたくなかった
I didn't want you to get involved.
もう…
Come on.
では最後に　37家門の皆さんに
Finally, I would like to inform you,
the Thirty-Seven Clans, of our new manifesto.
私たちの掲げる　新たな政策を告げます
地球に新たな領地と資源を得た私たちは
With our newly claimed land and resources on Earth, we no longer need rely on our homeworld of Vers.
何時までもヴァース本星に頼る必要はありません
Chicks grow and eventually must leave the nest to fly the skies. So shall we.
子はいずれ育ち　母の加護より離れ　自ら道を切り開くもの
わたくし　アセイラム・ヴァース・アリューシアは
I, Asseylum Vers Allusia,
スレイン・ザーツバルム・トロイヤード伯爵を夫に迎え
accept Count Slaine Saazbaum Troyard into my family as my husband,
この地球圏に…
and hereby announce that our new kingdom shall be here on Earth.
新たなる王国を築くことを宣言します
本字幕由诸神字幕组出品，仅供学习交流，禁止用于商业用途
更多中日双语字幕，尽在 i.kamigami.org 和微博 @诸神字幕组
日听:ikoko&Archer  翻译:mam&郝郝
校对:安少&zwx  时间轴:Foyzi  压制:河蟹
bokutachi wa samayoeru mirai
We are a future of dubious likelihood
僕たちは　彷徨える未来
窮屈な空に　ヒカリを探している
kyuukutsu na sora ni
We look to the oppressive sky
hikari wo sagashiteiru
in search of light
furueru te wa muryoku de
Our trembling hands are powerless
震える手は無力で
叫びはまだ遠くて
sakebi wa mata tookute
Our screams reach no one
dakedo tobu koto wo
But we will never be afraid
たけど飛ぶことを恐れてはいられない
osorete wa irarenai
of flying
永遠じゃなくても　完璧じゃなくても
eien ja nakutemo
We don't need eternity
kanpeki ja nakutemo
We don't need perfection
senaka-awase no sekai wo
We live in two related
背中合わせの世界を　真っ直ぐ生きてゆく
massugu ikiteyuku
but wildly different worlds
nando kizu tsuitemo
No matter the wounds we receive
何度傷ついても　何度間違えても
nando machigaetemo
and the mistakes we make,
unmei sae tobikoete yukou
we will overcome fate
運命さえ飛び越えていこう
kono sora no hate made
Until the skies above us end
この宙の果てまで
hajimari wo shinjite
we will believe in the genesis of a better life
創造を信じて
私にとって　お姉様は憧れでした
To me, you were always an unreachable dream, Sister.
美しくて　心優しくて　人々に愛されて
You were beautiful, kind of heart, and loved by your people.
私が持っていないものを持っていて
You had everything I did not.
でも一つだけ　私もお姉様と同じものを持っているの
However, you and I have one thing in common.
王家の血筋　アルドノアの起動因子
We both possess royal blood—
the Aldnoah activation factor.
それは　今のスレインに必要な力
A power that Slaine has need of.
私はスレインを選ぶことにしました
I have chosen Slaine.
スレインも私を選んでくれた
And he has been kind enough to choose me.
これからは　私がアセイラム・ヴァース・アリューシア
From now on, I will be Asseylum Vers Allusia.
私がお姉様…
I will be you.
だからもういいのよ　お姉様
So you can sleep now, Sister.
ウソよ
Just kidding.
たとえ人形でも　あなたは私のお姉様ですもの
Even as a senseless puppet, you are still my sister.
Sweet dreams.
いい夢を